#### Interests

ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE · COGNITIVE SCIENCE · NLP

My research broadly lies in the areas of human-centered computing. Specifically, I would like to advance the explainability of human behaviors by employing AI models, especially language processing.

### **Education**

#### Sungkyunkwan University (SKKU)

Seoul, South Korea

M.S. IN APPLIED ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE

Aug. 2020 - Feb. 2022

- · Advisor: Eunil Park
- · Master's Thesis: Understanding Difficulties of Content Filterings and Humans' Cognitive Bias in Algorithmic Recommendations

#### **Sungkyunkwan University**

Seoul, South Korea

B.A. IN PSYCHOLOGY

Mar. 2016 - Aug. 2020

B.S. IN ENGINEERING, INTERDISCIPLINARY PROGRAM OF CONVERGENT SOFTWARE - SAMSUNG CONVERGENCE

SOFTWARE COURSE

# Research Experience \_\_\_\_\_

# Researcher

European Cooperation in Science &

Technology

MULTIPLEYE

Sep. 2022 - Current

- · Collaborating with the researchers in the project, main researcher as Nora Hollenstein, (Group leader) Jamal Nasir.
- · Leading survey paper for using eye-tracking dataset to improve performance/explainability of NLP techniques.
- Revising the code for pre-processing eye-tracking dataset.

**Research Assistant** 

**FPFI** 

### DIGITAL HUMANITIES LAB

Apr. 2023 - Aug. 2023 (Expected) Advisor: Frederic Kaplan & Maud Ehrmann & Boros Emanuela

• Fine-tuning adapter module with low-resource historical dataset to deploy knowledge from large language model (LLaMA).

#### **Research Assistant**

NLP LAB

**FPFI** 

• Advisor: Antoine Bosselut & Lonneke van der Plas

- Conducted prompt tuning to implement chain-of-thought prompt for measuring creativity ability of large language models.
- Constructed Linux environment for large language model (e.g., OPT175B, BLOOM175B) in EPFL cluster.
- Conducted data analysis for newly constructed persona dialogue dataset (Accepted in ACL'23).

#### **Research Intern**

**CLAWS LAB** 

Georgia Institute of Technology

(Remote)

· Advisor: Srijan Kumar

Jul. 2021 - Apr. 2022

Sep. 2022 - Feb. 2023

- Engaged in survey paper on analyzing the countering misinformation efforts of the crowds.
- · Devised natural language processing method to debunk misinformation based on individual features of the crowds.

#### **Undergraduate Research Assistant**

SKKLI

DATA EXPERIENCE LAB · Advisor: Eunil Park

Jul. 2019 - Aug. 2020

- Explored user experience of augmented reality and virtual reality products (Funded by NRF of Korea)
- Developed a Deep Learning Model for Predicting Service Reuse (Funded by the NRF of Korea)

# **Publication**

j: journal · c: conference · Equal Contribution · Corresponding Author\*

c4 Silin Gao, Beatriz Borges<sup>1</sup>, Soyoung Oh<sup>1</sup>, Deniz Bayzit<sup>1</sup>, Saya Kanno, Hiromi Wakaki, Yuki Mitsufuji, & Antoine Bosselut (2023). PeaCoK: Persona Commonsense Knowledge for Consistent and Engaging Narratives. ACL 2023. [PDF]

MAY 30, 2023 Soyoung Oh c3 Soyoung Oh, & Eunil Park (2022).

Are you aware of what you are watching? Role of machine heuristic in online content recommendations. ICWSM 2022 Workshop on Cyber Social Threats (CySoc 2022). [PDF]

c2 Sangeun Lee<sup>1</sup>, Soyoung Oh<sup>1</sup>, Minji Kim, & Eunil Park (2022).

Measuring Embedded Human-like Bias in Face Recognition Models. AAAI 2022 Workshop on Artificial Intelligence with Biased or Scarce Data (AIBSD 2022). [PDF]

**c1** Soyoung Oh<sup>1</sup>, Jisu Kim<sup>1</sup>, Seungpeel Lee.<sup>1</sup>, & Eunil Park (2021).

Jujeop: Korean Puns for K-pop Stars on Social Media. In Proceedings of the Ninth International Workshop on Natural Language Processing for Social Media 2021, NAACL HLT'21 Workshop. [PDF]

j7 Dahye Jeong<sup>1</sup>, Soyoung Oh<sup>1</sup>, & Eunil Park (2022).

DemoHash: Hashtag Recommendation based on User Demographic Information. Expert Systems With Applications. [HTML]

**j6** Soyoung Oh, Honggeun Ji, Jina Kim, & Eunil Park (2022).

Deep learning model based on expectation confirmation theory to predict customer satisfaction in hospitality service. Information Technology & Tourism. [HTML]

**j5** Honggeun Ji, **Soyoung Oh**, Jina Kim, & Eunil Park (2022).

Integrating Deep Learning and Machine Translation for Understanding Unrefined Languages. CMC-Computers, Materials & Continua, 70(1), 669–678. [HTML]

j4 Jina Kim, Honggeun Ji, Soyoung Oh, Syjung Hwang, Eunil Park, & del Pobil, A. P. (2021).

A deep hybrid learning model for customer repurchase behavior. Journal of Retailing and Consumer Services (SSCI, JCR 2019 IF=4.219, Q2 in Business). [HTML]

j3 Jina Kim, Yeonju Jang, Kunwoo Bae, **Soyoung Oh**, Namjeong Jeong, Eunil Park, & del Pobil, A. P. (2021). Between comments and repeat visit: capturing repeat visitors with a hybrid approach. Data Technologies and Applications. [HTML]

**j2 Soyoung Oh**, Jina Kim, Honggeun Ji, Eunil Park, Jinyoung Han, Minsam Ko, & Moonyoung Lee (2020). Cross-cultural Comparison of Interactive Streaming Services: Evidence from Twitch. Telematics and Informatics, ISSN: 0736-5853 (SSCI, JCR 2019 IF=4.139, Q1 in Information Science & Library Science). [HTML]

j1 Jina Kim, Soyeon Shin, Kunwoo Bae, Soyoung Oh, Eunil Park, & del Pobil, A. P. (2020).
Can AI be a content creator? Effects of content creators and information delivery methods on the psychology of content consumers.
Telematics and Informatics, ISSN: 0736-5853 (SSCI, JCR 2019 IF=4.139, Q1 in Information Science & Library Science). [HTML]

# Teaching Experience \_\_\_\_\_

Teaching Assistant EPFL

CS486, INTERACTION DESIGN

Spring semester, 2023

· Assisted making and grading assignments in the field of HCI.

Teaching Assistant SKKU

AAl3020, Dept. of Applied Artificial Intelligence at Undergraduate Course

Fall semester, 2020

Led research project with undergraduate students and successfully submitted paper to conference [c2]

Instruction Assistant KINTEX, South Korea

IOT Maker Booth @ E2FESTA2018

Sept. 2018

· Assisted making IoT lamp with Arduino

# Work Experience

#### Silikal Korea Construction Chemicals Co., Ltd.

Seoul, South Korea

INTERN

May 2018 - Jul. 2018

· Done internship program with logistics, sales, and accounting.

Silikal GmbH Mainhausen, Germany

INTERN

Feb. 2018 - Apr. 2018

- Done internship program at sales & sales support in Export, Import division.

### **Honors & Awards**.

2022	Attendance Scholarship, ICWSM-2022 Grant Program	ICWSM
2022	EDIC Fellowship, A one-year fellowship	EPFL
2021	Attendance Scholarship, ICWSM-2021 Grant Program	ICWSM
2020	Bachelor's Degree Linked Master Program Scholarship, Full tuition of last semester of undergraduate	SKKU
2019	Travel Scholarship, Language Exchange student @ Okayama University	Campus Asia
2019	Academic Excellence Scholarship. 70% of tuition from Dept. of Social Science (GPA:4.4/4.5)	SKKU

## Academic Services \_\_\_\_\_

2022	Student Volunteer, ICWSM'22 Virtual Conference	ICWSM
2022	Student Volunteer, FAccT'22 On-Site Conference	FAccT
2022	Reviewer, Reviewed papers @ alt.chi track	CHI
2021	Student Volunteer, NAACL HLT'21 Virtual Conference	NAACL

# Skills\_\_\_\_\_

Programming Python, SPSS, LaTeX, JAVA, C
Machine Learning Tensorflow, Keras, Pytorch
HTML, CSS, Node.js

**User Research** Interviewing, Conducting surveys, Experimental Design

**Languages** Korean, English, Japanese

### References\_\_\_\_

**Eunil Park** eunilpark@skku.edu, Assistant Professor @ Sungkyunkwan University **Antoine Bosselut** antoine.bosselut@epfl.ch, Tenure Track Assistant Professor @ EPFL **Lonneke van der Plas** lonneke.vanderplas@idiap.ch, Professor @ IDIAP